<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN" 
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd"[
	<!ENTITY legal SYSTEM "legal.xml">
  	<!ENTITY appversion "0.4.0">
  	<!ENTITY manrevision "0.1">
  	<!ENTITY date "September 2005">
  	<!ENTITY app "Roadster">
]>
  
<book id="index">
<title>&app; Guide</title>

	<bookinfo> 
	 	<copyright> 
			<year>2005</year>
			<holder>Ian McIntosh</holder> 
		</copyright>

<!-- translators: uncomment this:
  		<copyright>
   			<year>2005</year>
   			<holder>ME-THE-TRANSLATOR (Latin translation)</holder>
  		</copyright>
-->

	<publisher> 
		<publishername>&app; Documentation Project</publishername>
	 </publisher>
	&legal; 
	 <authorgroup>
	 	<author> 
	 		<firstname>Ian</firstname>
			<surname>McIntosh</surname> 
			<affiliation> 
				<orgname>&app; Documentation Project</orgname>
				<address><email>ian_mcintosh@linuxadvocate.org</email> </address>
			</affiliation>
		</author>
	</authorgroup>

<!-- According to GNU FDL, revision history is mandatory if you are -->
<!-- modifying/reusing someone else's document.  If not, you can omit it. -->

	<releaseinfo>This manual describes version &appversion; of &app;.</releaseinfo>

	<legalnotice> 
		<title>Feedback</title>
		<para>
			To report a bug or offer feedback about 
			<application>&app;</application> or this help document, follow 
			the directions on the <ulink url="ghelp:gnome-feedback" type="help">
			&app; Feedback Page</ulink>. 
      	</para>

	<!-- Translators may also add here feedback address for translations -->

	</legalnotice>
	</bookinfo>
<!-- ============= Working with Roadster ============================== -->
<chapter id="basics">
	<title>Using &app;</title>
	<highlights>
		<para>This chapter explains the windows and XXX of &app;</para>
	</highlights>

	<section id="mainwindow">
		<title>Main Window</title>
			<screenshot>
			<mediaobject> 
				<imageobject> 
					<imagedata fileref="figures/window_layout.png" format="PNG"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</screenshot>
		<para>
		The main window.  The individual parts of this window are described below.
		</para>
    
        <section id="toolbar">
            <title>Toolbar</title>
            <para>
            The toolbar is the horizontal bar across the top of the &app; window.  It provides access to the most useful map navigation operations:
            </para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                <para>
                <guibutton>Back Button.</guibutton> The Back button takes you to the last place you were looking at.  It works in a similar way to the Back button in your web browser.
                No matter how you move the map, clicking Back will undo the movement.
                </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                <para>
                <guibutton>Forward Button.</guibutton> After using the Back button, you can click Forward to return to where you were.  It works in a similar way to the Forward button in your web browser.
                </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                <para id="back-button">
                <guibutton>Zoom-Out Button.</guibutton>  Zoom out one level.  When you are zoomed out as far as possible, the button will be grayed out and unavailable.
                </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                <para>
                <guibutton>Zoom Slider.</guibutton> The slider allows you to quickly zoom to any level.  Click and drag the slider to zoom.
                </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                <para>
                <guibutton>Zoom-In Button.</guibutton>  Zoom in one level.  When you are zoomed in as far as possible, the button will be grayed out and unavailable.
                </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                <para>
                <guibutton>Search Entry.</guibutton> Read more about searching in the section titled <link linkend="search">How to Search</link>.
                </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            <para>To hide the toolbar, choose <menuchoice><guimenu>View</guimenu><guimenuitem>Toolbar</guimenuitem></menuchoice>. To display the
  toolbar again, choose <menuchoice><guimenu>View</guimenu><guimenuitem>Toolbar</guimenuitem></menuchoice> again. </para>
        </section>

        <section id="sidebar">
            <title>Sidebar</title>
            <para>
                The sidebar is the vertical bar on the right edge of the &app; window.  It has three tabs:
            </para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <guibutton>1.Locations.</guibutton> The Locations list shows a list of types of Locations, and allows you to show or hide each type of Location.  For example, you could
                        choose to show all Restaurants.  To show a type of Location, set the checkbox next to it to "on" (checked).  To hide a type of
                        Location, set the checkbox next to it to "off" (unchecked).
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <guibutton>2.Tracks.</guibutton> The Tracks tab shows a list of your Tracks, and allows you to show or hide individual Tracks.  To show a Track, set 
                        the checkbox next to it to "on" (checked).  To hide a Track, set the checkbox next to it to "off" (unchecked).
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <guibutton>3.Results.</guibutton>
                        The Results Tab shows a list of the search results from your most recent search.  Clicking on a search
                        result will move the map to show you that road or Location.  Clicking the Back button on the toolbar will return you to where you previously were.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            <para>To hide the sidebar, choose <menuchoice><guimenu>View</guimenu><guimenuitem>Sidebar</guimenuitem></menuchoice>. To display the
  sidebar again, choose <menuchoice><guimenu>View</guimenu><guimenuitem>Sidebar</guimenuitem></menuchoice> again. </para>
        </section>

        <section id="map-area">
            <title>Map Area</title>
            <para>
            XXX
            </para>
        </section>
    </section>
</chapter>


<chapter id="search">
<title>How to Search</title>
    <highlights>
        <para>
        This chapter will show you how to perform searches in &app; and offers some tips for improving the results you get.
        </para>
    </highlights>

    <section id="search-basics">
        <title>Search Basics</title>

        <section>
            <title>Search Basics</title>
            <para>
            To start a search, enter search words into the search box in the upper right corner of the <link linkend="mainwindow">main window</link>, and then hit the <keycap>Enter</keycap> key on your keyboard.  Some example searches you could try now:
            </para>
            <itemizedlist>
            <listitem><para>120 Main Street, Orleans, Massachusetts</para></listitem>
            <listitem><para>Buffalo Street, ND</para></listitem>
            <listitem><para>Miami</para></listitem>
            <listitem><para>Arizona</para></listitem>
            <listitem><para>90210</para></listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            <para>
            After performing a search, the search results sidebar tab will automatically be displayed.  Click on one of the results to view the location.
            </para>
            <note>
                <para>
                    Don't worry about losing your current spot, you can use the <guibutton>Back Button</guibutton> to return to it later.
                </para>
            </note>
        </section>

        <section>
            <title>Searching for Locations</title>
            <para>
            The search box can also find places like restaurants, schools, and police stations.  Try these searches:
            </para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem><para>pizza in Portland, OR</para></listitem>
                <listitem><para>coffee shop wifi Cambridge</para></listitem>
                <listitem><para>gas</para></listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            <para>
            Notice that some searches have a city name in them.  When you include a city name at the end of your search words, &app; will try to find Places in or near that city.
            </para>
            <para>
            When you don't specify a city in your search, &app; will find Places nearby where you are currently looking.
            </para>
        </section>
    </section>

    <section id="search-tips">
    <title>Search Tips</title>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem><para>When searching in &app;, capitalization doesn't matter.  The word PIZZA is treated the same as Pizza and even PiZZa.  They will all get the same results.</para></listitem>
            <listitem><para>Punctuation like commas, quotation marks, pluses, minuses, and parentheses are ignored.</para></listitem>
            <listitem><para>Words like "in" or "near" are optional.  They wilk not change the results you get.</para></listitem>
            <listitem><para>If you get too many search results, try adding more search words.</para></listitem>
            <listitem><para>If you get too few search results, try removing one or more search words.</para></listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </section>

</chapter>

</book>
